A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Early Files, Personal and Professional papers, RG 1 FA1858
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Naval Service - Bureau of Aeronautics - Instructional Pamphlets (Nos. 11-26) (2 folders), 1942-1943 (Box 14, Folder 149-150)
- Naval Service - Bureau of Aeronautics - Instructional Pamphlets, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 151)
- Naval Service - Bureau of Aeronautics - Instructions, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 152)
- Naval Service - Bureau of Aeronautics - Memoranda and Reports (4 Folders), 1942-1945, undated (Box 14, Folder 153-156)
  Files include LSR manuscript notes; 3 unidentifed photos (in folders 154 and 156); and various tables and charts. Folder 153 also includes a copy of a letter from Jesse H. Knight to Harold [N. Marsh], July 8, 1942, that appears to be filed here accidentally.
- Naval Service - Bureau of Aeronautics - Memoranda and Reports - Oversized Drawings, 1943-1945 (Folder 1)
  Oversized drawings and charts separated from Box 14, folders 154-156:
  Folder 154: Analysis of Production Loading for Airplane Departments (June 1943 - ). [27" x 22"]
  Folder 155: General Layout GACA Buildings and Airport, March 27, 1944. Plant Planning Drawing no. PP369-1. Inscription: Encl. (2), BAR ltr. 4-10-44. [15" x 17"]
  G.A.C. Plant Layout, Goodyear Aircraft Corporation, Arizona Division, Litchfield Park, Arizona, December 7, 1943. Plant Planning Drawing no. PP371-4. Negative photostatic copy. [10" x 19"]
  Folder 156: Daily Production Progress Report. Bureau of Aeronautics Representative, Consolidated Vultee Aircraft Corporation, New Orleans Division, January 16, 1945. [14" x 27"]
  Airplane Production Progress Report, Model FR-1 Airplane, W-13 Schedule Excluding Spares, Posted through March 18, 1945. Ryan Aeronautical Co., Lindbergh Field, San Diego, California. Photostatic print. Two copies (one separated, and one retained in the file). [11" x 22"]
  Bureau of Aeronautics, Analysis of Naval Production Airframe Contracts, January 1, 1941 through April 30, 1945. 7 pp. [17" x 22"]
  Bureau of Aeronautics, Average Unit Contract Prices Navy Airplanes. May 1, 1945. 4 pages, plus Appendix (1 page). [17" x 22"]
- Naval Service - Bureau of Aeronautics - Procurement Division (Box 14, Folder 157)
- Naval Service - Clippings and Postcards, 1942-1945, undated (Box 14, Folder 158)
- Naval Service - Flight Schedules and Maps, 1942-1945 (Box 15, Folder 159)
- Naval Service - Foreign Economic Administration, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 160)
  File contains: Statement Submitted by Leo T. Crowley, Foreign Economic Administrator, before the Sub-Committee on War Mobilization of the Senate Military Affairs Committee, on the subject: "Germany's Economic Base for Aggression," June 26, 1945.
- Naval Service - Manuals, 1942-1943 (Box 15, Folder 161)
  Reference Manual, United States Navy Teachers Kit; Manual of Information and Operational Procedures for Naval Officers Dealing with Manpower Problems of Navy Bureau of Aeronautics Contractors.
- Naval Service - Navy Regulations and Customs Course, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 162)
  Includes assignments and LSR's responses.
- Naval Service - Notes on Interviews and Meetings, 1942-1945 (Box 15, Folder 163)
  LSR manuscript notes.
- Naval Service - LSR Personal Records, 1942-1945 (Box 15, Folder 164)
  Includes LSR's commission as Lietuenant (junior grade) in the U.S. Naval Reserve, March 3, 1942; calling card and copper printing plate; assignments; travel allowances; resignation request.
- Naval Service - LSR Personal Records, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 164A)
  Restricted - Health records - Open in 2042
- Naval Service - Printed Material, 1943, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 165)
  Congressional reports and other publications on postwar planning and war plant disposal.
- Naval Service - Travel Vouchers, 1942-1945 (Box 15, Folder 166)
- Naval Service - Trip Notes, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 167)
  Spiral bound reporter's notebooks, containing LSR's notes on visits and discussions.
- Naval Service - Trip Notes (5 Folders), 1943-1945, undated (Box 16, Folder 168-172)
  Spiral bound reporter's notebooks, containing LSR's notes on visits and discussions..
- LSR Notes, Clippings, and Pamphlets, 1927, 1933-1934, 1947, 1983, undated (Box 16, Folder 173)
  Includes Standard Oil Company "Information for Employees" booklet, 1927.
- Clippings, Pamphlets, and Notes, 1923-1932 (Box 16, Folder 174-175)
  Folder 174 includes Lucy Truman Aldrich's account of her "Week-End with Chinese Bandits" (1923); New York Times and Philadelphia Evening Bulletin articles on the Grenfell Mission, 1930; and miscellaneous clippings concerning friends and family. Folder 175 includes a copy of JDR Jr's address at the Dedication of the Chapel at the University of Chicago, October 28, 1928; plus various clippings and notes on Philosophy and other topics.
- Pamphlets, 1897-1930 (Box 16, Folder 176)
  Includes pamphlets by John D. Rockefeller, JDR Jr., Wallace Buttrick, J. Lionberger Davis, Harry Emerson Fosdick, and several others.
- Appointment Books, 1929-1935 (Box 17, Folder 177)
- Naval Service - Separated Oversized Publications, circa 1941-1945 (Box 18)
  Oversized publications and pamphlets from Boxes 13-15, folders 147-165:
  Box 13, Folder 147:
  Lockheed Log, Vol. 3, no. 4, undated
  Boeing Stratocruiser. Boeing Aircraft Company publication, undated.
  Box 14, Folder 151:
  Broadside pamphlet: "Order Early: Aircraft Materials and Components. Time Flow Charts for Selected Aircraft Components." Prepared for Aircraft Scheduling Unit by Resources Control Section Production Division. AAF Material Command, Wright Field, Dayton, Ohio, 27 March 1944.
  Box 14, Folder 158:
  "Outfitting a War Lady." Etching by Kent Hagerman, of the U.S.S. Piedmont under construction. Distributed by the Tampa Shipbuilding Company, undated.
  Air Ads, Vol. 1, no. 13, January 20, 1945. Published in the Interests of the Central States Air Men, St. Cloud, MN.
  Box 15, Folder 165:
  The Navy Plan for National Security. US Navy Department. Undated broadside pamphlet.